Finding Aid for the Avant-Garde Poetry Tape Recordings LSC.0961
UCLA Library Special Collections
Avant-garde poetry tape recordings
1966-1967
UCLA Library Special Collections
Silverton, Michael
WBAI Radio (New York, N.Y.)
WNYC (Radio station: New York, N.Y.)
LSC.0961
3.0 Linear Feet (42 open reel audiotapes)
Collection consists of 42 reel-to-reel tapes recorded by Michael Silverton for an avant-garde poetry series for New York radio station WNYC in 1966, and another for radio station WBAI in 1967.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audiovisual materials. Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access, unless otherwise noted in a Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the file level. All requests to access processed materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942335963606533
Scope and Content
Collection consists of 42 reel-to-reel tapes recorded by Michael Silverton for an avant-garde poetry series for New York radio station WNYC in 1966, and another for radio station WBAI in 1967. Interviewees include: Kenneth Koch, John Ashbery, Allan Kaplan, Jerome Rothenberg, Michael Benedikt, Russell Edson, Kenward Elmslie, Ted Berrigan, Joseph Ceravolo, Sotere Torregian, Lorenzo Thomas, John Perreault, Aram Saroyan, Jim Brodey, Peter Schjeedahl, Dick Gallup, Kathy Frazer, Tony Towle, Frank O'Hara (memorial), A. Schweiner, David Antin, Ted Greenwald, Lewis Warsh, Anne Waldman, Shelley Slater, Frank Kuenstler, Frank Lima, Gerald Hopman, Paul Blackburn, Joe Brainard, Stanley Moss, Michael O'Brien, Tom Clark, Ron Padgett, Don Gardner, Michael Brownstein, Milton Gilman, Robert Gilman, and Barton Midwood.
Source of Description
Description derived from in-house card file.
Poets, American -- 20th century -- Audiotapes.
- Poetry of the Avant Garde series on WNYC, 1966; 19 Reels (10.5) 7.5 per second
  Scope and Contents
  19 open reel audiotapes recorded by Michael Silverton for a series of radio broadcasts entitled, Poetry of the Avant Garde.
  Contents:
  Reel 1: Kenneth Koch
  Reel 2: John Ashbery
  Reel 3: Allan Kaplan
  Reel 4: Jerome Rothenberg
  Reel 5: Michael Benedikt
  Reel 6: Russell Edson
  Reel 7: Kenward Elmslie
  Reel 8: Ted Berrigan
  Reel 9: Joseph Ceravolo
  Reel 10: Sotere Torregian
  Reel 11: Lorenzo Thomas
  Reel 12: John Perreault
  Reel 13: Aram Saroyan
  Reel 14: Jim Brodey
  Reel 15: Peter Schjeedahl
  Reel 16: Dick Gallup
  Reel 17: Kathy Frazer
  Reel 18: Tony Towle
  Reel 19: Frank O'Hara Memorial
  - Poetry of the Avant Garde: John Ashbery, 1966 February 3; yrlsc_0961_001_001; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:54:51) (Box 1, Case 1)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are available for access. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
    Transcribed from container: "John Ashbery readings for 'Poetry of The Avant Garde' for WNYC, NY Thurs June 2, 1960. Recorded Feb 3, 1966"
  - Poetry of the Avant Garde: Michael Benedikt, 1966-1967; 1966 June 23; yrlsc_0961_001_002; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:57:20) (Box 1, Case 2)
    Content note: Program begins at 0:02:21 and ends at 0:48:00 with music before and after the program. Transcribed from container: "No.5 Poetry of the Av.-Garde Michael Benedikt/Michael Silverton. DON NOT ERASE! AIR 6/23/66 10-10:55pm Thurs"
  - Poetry of the Avant Garde: Ted Berrigan, 1966-1967; 1966 July 14; yrlsc_0961_001_003; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:53:14) (Box 1, Case 3)
    Content note: Program begins at 0:51:00 with music before. Transcribed from container: "Ted Berrigan Reading. Poetry of the Av-GDE. Silverton. for b'cast Thurs 10pm (AM only) July 14, 1966"
  - Poetry of the Avant Garde: James Brodey, 1966-1967; yrlsc_0961_001_004; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:55:19) (Box 1, Case 4)
    Transcribed from container: "Jim Brodey. 'Poetry of the Avant Garde' for b'cast Sept 1 Thurs nite 10PM (AM radio only) produced by Mike Silverton"
  - Poetry of the Avant Garde: Joseph Ceravolo, 1966-1967; 1966 July 21; yrlsc_0961_001_005; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:55:50) (Box 1, Case 5)
    Transcribed from container: "Poetry of the Avant-Garde Joseph Ceravolo for b'cast Thurs. 10PM July 21, 1966"
  - Poetry of the Avant Garde: Russell Edson, 1966-1967; yrlsc_0961_001_006; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:55:42) (Box 1, Case 6)
    Content note: Program begins at 0:01:08 and ends at 0:51:13 with music before and after. Transcribed from container: "Poetry of the Av. Gde Russell Edson Readings No.6 in series. For b'cast Thurs, 10PM 9AM only) June 30"
  - Poetry of the Avant Garde: Kenward Elmslie, 1966 May 11; yrlsc_0961_001_007; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:58:45) (Box 1, Case 7)
    Transcribed from container: "No.7 May 11, 1966 Poetrty of the Avant Garde. Kenward Elmslie reading. for b'cast Thurs 10pm (AM only) July 7"
  - Introduction Music, undated; yrlsc_0961_001_008; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:50:00) (Box 1, Case 8)
    Content note: Introduction music. Information on container does not match reel
  - Poetry of the Avant Garde: Allan Kaplan, 1966-1967; yrlsc_0961_001_009; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:58:00) (Box 1, Case 9)
    Content note: Program begins at 0:48:00. Information on container does not match reel
  - Poetry of the Avant Garde: John Perrault, 1966-1967; 1966 August 18; yrlsc_0961_001_010; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:58:55) (Box 1, Case 10)
    Transcribed from container: "Poetry of the Vant-garde. Michael Silverton. John Perreault reading. Ready for b'cast Thurs 10pm Aug 18, 1966"
  - Poetry of the Avant Garde: Jerome Rothernberg, 1966 February 3; 1966 June 9; yrlsc_0961_001_011; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:55:29) (Box 1, Case 11)
    Transcribed from container: "No.2 Jerome Rothenberg Reading; Ready for b'cast thurs June 9, 1966. Property of Michael Silverton 63 8 Ave BKLYN 11217
  - Poetry of the Avant Garde: Aram Saroyan, 1966-1967; 1966 August 25; yrlsc_0961_001_012; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:58:58) (Box 1, Case 12)
    Transcribed from container: "Poetry of the Acvant-Garde poet Aram Saroyan for b'cast Aug 25 Thurs nite 10PM (AM radio only). Produced by Mike Silverton
  - Poetry of the Avant Garde: Peter Schjeedahl, 1966-1967; 1966 September 8; yrlsc_0961_001_013; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:55:37) (Box 1, Case 13)
    Transcribed from container: "Peter Schjeedahl Poetry of the Avant Garde for b'cast Sept 8 Thurs nite 10PM (AM radio only) Produced by Mike Silverton"
  - Poetry of the Avant Garde: Lorenzo Thomas, 1966-1967; 1966 August 11; yrlsc_0961_001_014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:55:36) (Box 1, Case 14)
    Transcribed from container: "Lorenzo Thomas. Ready fro b'cast Thurs 10pm Aug 11, 1966"
  - Poetry of the Avant Garde: Sotere Torregian, 1966-1967; yrlsc_0961_001_015; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:56:35) (Box 1, Case 15)
    Content note: Program begins at 0:01:00
  - Poetry of the Avant Garde: Kathy Frazer, 1966-1967; yrlsc_0961_003_002; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:53:19) (Box 3, Case 2)
    Transcribed from container: "Poetry of the Avant Garde Poet Kathy Frazer reading. Michael Silverton for b'cast Thurs. Sept 22"
  - Poetry of the Avant Garde: Dick Gallup, 1966-1967; yrlsc_0961_003_003; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:55:36) (Box 3, Case 3)
    Transcribed from container: "Poetry of the Avant Garde Poet Dick Gallup reading. Michael Silverton for b'cast Thurs. Sept 15"
  - Poetry of the Avant Garde: Frank O'Hara Memorial, 1966-1967; yrlsc_0961_003_008; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:54:33) (Box 3, Case 8)
    Content note: Memorial for Frank O'Hara featuring readings of his work by Kenneth Koch, John Ashbery, Bill Berkson, Tony Towle, Ted Berrigan, Joseph Ceravolo, David Shapiro, Jim Brodey, Aram Saroyan, Sotère Torregian
  - Poetry of the Avant Garde: Tony Towle, 1966-1967; yrlsc_0961_003_011; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:54:07) (Box 3, Case 11)
    Transcribed from container: "Poetry of the Avant Garde poet: Tony Towle for b'cast Sept. 29"
- New York Poets series on WBAI, 1967; 23 Reels (7 and 10.5)
  Scope and Content
  23 open reel audiotapes recorded by Michael Silverton for a series of broadcasts entitled, New York Poets.
  Reel 1 (10.5): A. Schweiner
  Reel 2: Russell Edson
  Reel 3: David Antin
  Reel 4: Ted Greenwald
  Reel 5: Lewis Warsh
  Reel 6: Anne Waldman
  Reel 7 (10.5): Shelley Slater
  Reel 8: Frank Kuenstler
  Reel 9: Frank Lima
  Reel 10: Gerald Hopman
  Reel 11: Paul Blackburn
  Reel 12: Kenward Elmslie
  Reel 13: Joe Brainard
  Reel 14: Stanley Moss
  Reel 15: Michael O'Brien
  Reel 16: Tom Clark
  Reel 17: Ted Berrigan
  Reel 18: Ron Padgett
  Reel 19: Don Gardner
  Reel 20: Michael Brownstein
  Reel 21: Milton Gilman
  Reel 22: Robert Kelly
  Reel 23 (10.5): Barton Midwood
  - New York Poets: Gerald Hopman, 1966-1967; 1967 June 20; yrlsc_0961_002_009; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:29:30) (Box 2, Case 9)
    Transcribed from container: "New York Poets for WBAI. Michael Silverton 90 8AV Brooklyn 11215. Poet: Gerald Hopman. ready for broadcast June 20"
  - New York Poets: Frank Kuenstler, 1967 March 20; 1967 May 29; yrlsc_0961_002_010; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:30:05) (Box 2, Case 10)
    Transcribed from container: "New York Poets #8. Poet: Frank Kuenstler March 20, 1967. Property of M. Silverton 90 8AV. BRKLYN"
  - New York Poets: Frank Lima, 1967 April 12; 1967 June 6; yrlsc_0961_002_011; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:29:36) (Box 2, Case 11)
    Transcribed from container: "New York Poets #15. Poet Michael O'Brien. produced by Michael Silverton. Ready for Broadcast"
  - New York Poets: Stanley Moss, 1967 May 30; yrlsc_0961_002_012; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:30:17) (Box 2, Case 12)
    Transcribed from container: "New York Poets #14 for WBAI. Ready for Broadcast. Note: the intro of this tape occurs after 1st poem"
  - New York Poets: Michael O'Brien, 1967 June 5; yrlsc_0961_002_013; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:28:39) (Box 2, Case 13)
  - New York Poets: Ron Padgett, 1967 June 8; yrlsc_0961_002_014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:27:24) (Box 2, Case 14)
    Transcribed from container: "New York Poets #18 (WBAI). poet Ron Padgett.Ready for Broadcast. Note: it may be necessary to adjust the gain several times"
  - New York Poets: Anne Waldman, 1966 December 5; 1967 April 25; yrlsc_0961_002_015; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:31:11) (Box 2, Case 15)
    Transcribed from container: "No. 6 in the series for WBAI"
  - New York Poets: Lewis Warsh, 1966 December 12; 1967 April 11; yrlsc_0961_002_016; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:31:20) (Box 2, Case 16)
    Transcribed from container: "No. 5 in the series for WBAI"
  - New York Poets: Ted Greenwald, 1967-03-28T00:00:00+00:00; March 28, 1967; yrlsc_0961_002_008; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:30:51) (Box 2, Case 8)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Transcribed from container: "No. 4 in the series for WBAI"
  - New York Poets: Kenward Elmslie, 1967 May 5; yrlsc_0961_002_007; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:20:39) (Box 2, Case 7)
    Transcribed from container: "New York Poets #12. Poet: Kenward Elmslie. Ready for Broadcast"
  - New York Poets: Russell Edson, 1966-1967; 1967 February 23; yrlsc_0961_002_006; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:31:12) (Box 2, Case 6)
    Transcribed from container: "New York Poets #2. poet: Russell Edson"
  - New York Poets: Tom Clark, 1967 June 8; yrlsc_0961_002_005; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:30:24) (Box 2, Case 5)
    Transcribed from container: "New York Poets #16. poet Tom Clark. Ready for Broadcast"
  - New York Poets: Joe Brainard, 1967 May 5; yrlsc_0961_002_004; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:29:45) (Box 2, Case 4)
    Transcribed from container: "New York Poets #13. poet Joe Brainard. Ready for Broadcast"
  - New York Poets: Paul Blackburn, 1967 April 13; yrlsc_0961_002_003; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:30:03) (Box 2, Case 3)
    Transcribed from container: "New York Poets #13. poet Paul Blackburn. Ready for Broadcast- July"
  - New York Poets: Ted Barrigan, 1967 June 8; yrlsc_0961_002_002; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:28:41) (Box 2, Case 2)
    Transcribed from container: "New York Poets #17. Poet: Ted Barrigan. Ready for Broadcast"
  - New York Poets: David Antin, 1966 November 14; 1967 March 15; yrlsc_0961_002_001; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:29:19) (Box 2, Case 1)
    Transcribed from container: "New York Poets: David Antin Reading. No. 3 in the series for WBAI."
  - New York Poets: Michael Brownstein, 1967 June 26; yrlsc_0961_003_001; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:28:00) (Box 3, Case 1)
    Transcribed from container: "New York Poets #20 (WBAI). Poet: Michael Brownstein. Ready for Broadcast"
  - New York Poets: Donald Gardner, 1967 June 12; yrlsc_0961_003_004; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:28:18) (Box 3, Case 4)
    Transcribed from container: "New York Poets #19. Poet: Donald Gardner. This tape is property of Michael Silverton 90 8AV Brooklyn 11215. Ready for Broadcast"
  - New York Poets: Milton Gilman, 1967 July 5; yrlsc_0961_003_005; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:29:44) (Box 3, Case 5)
    Transcribed from container: "New Yokr Poets #21. Poet: Milton Gilman. This tape is property of Michael Silverton 90 8AV Brooklyn 11215. Ready for Broadcast"
  - New York Poets: Robert Kelly, 1967 July 13; yrlsc_0961_003_006; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:30:33) (Box 3, Case 6)
    Transcribed from container: "New York Poets #22. Poet: Robert Kelly. This tape is property of Michael Silverton 90 8AV Brooklyn 11215. Prodiced for WBAI by Michael Silverton"
  - New York Poets: Prose Occasional, 1966-1967; yrlsc_0961_003_007; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:05:44) (Box 3, Case 7)
    Content note: Container labeled as both Shelley Slater #7 and Barton Midwood #23, but recording features only Barton Midwood
  - New York Poets: Armand Schwerner, 1966-1967; yrlsc_0961_003_009; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:38:34) (Box 3, Case 9)
    Content note: The correct name of the poet is Armand Schwerner. Finding aid is incorrect. Transcribed from container: "New York Poets I: A. Schwerner"
  - New York Poets: Prose Occasional, 1966-1967; yrlsc_0961_003_010; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:06:00) (Box 3, Case 10)
    Content note: Duplicate of yrlsc_0961_003_007. Information on container does not match reel